newsmax.com 2019-12-12

# Newsmax.com - Privacy Statement

**Effective Date: July 15, 2019**

Newsmax Media, Inc., and its affiliates (“Newsmax,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) owns and operates newsmax.com, newsmaxtv.com, w3.newsmax.com, shop.newsmax.com, simplehearttest.com, newsmaxfeednetwork.com, and any affiliated sites (collectively, the “Sites”) as well as makes the same or similar content available via e-mail (“E-mail Content”) and to mobile devices via its apps (“Mobile Content”). The Sites, E-mail Content, Mobile Content, the Feeds (as defined below), subscription services offered by Newsmax (“Services”), and all related content and products thereto, are collectively referred to herein as “Newsmax Offerings.” BY USING THE NEWSMAX OFFERINGS, YOU SIGNIFY YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND OF OUR PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU SHOULD NOT USE THE NEWSMAX OFFERINGS.

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect your Personal Data (as defined below) on the Newsmax Offerings, how we collect, use, and protect such data, and the choices you have concerning our use of such data. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. This Privacy Policy represents our current (as of the last revised date, above) data collection and usage practices.

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by the Newsmax Offerings. We are not responsible for the privacy of any information (i) that you reveal or post in any public forum that may be or in the future become available on the Newsmax Offerings, such as message boards or chat rooms, (ii) that is available to the general public through no action or fault of Newsmax, (iii) that Newsmax receives from any third party reasonably known to have a legal right to transmit such information and under no obligation to keep such information confidential, or (iv) that originates from websites that are operated or owned by third parties that may be linked to or from the Newsmax Offerings.

**Data Collection**

Personal Data is information that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you, such as your name, e-mail address, postal address, or phone number (“Personal Data”). Newsmax collects Personal Data from you when you enroll in, subscribe to, or agree to purchase any of our paid goods and services, register for news alerts on the Newsmax Offerings, or voluntarily provide it to us, such as name, postal address, email address, phone number, financial information, employment information, gender, demographic information including age, and information about your personal opinions or beliefs. In addition to information collected during registration, enrollment, subscription, or purchase, Newsmax collects Personal Data knowingly provided by you in e-mails to the Newsmax Offerings, online forms, order and registration forms, surveys, polls, sweepstakes, data provided through commenting features, and contest entries. This includes sensitive Personal Data including political opinions, religious affiliation, and health information.

Newsmax also collects “Monitoring Data." Monitoring Data includes computer or device type, IP address or other device identifiers, browser information, app usage data, information collected through cookies and other technologies, demographic information, statistical and aggregated information. We may use Monitoring Data to help us understand who uses the Newsmax Offerings and to improve Newsmax’s websites. Some Monitoring Data may also be Personal Data.

We will not sell, share, license, trade, or rent your Personal Data or other information, other than as specified in this Privacy Policy.

**Use of Tracking Tools**

To enhance the Internet experience on the Newsmax Offerings, Newsmax and service providers it engages may use various Internet technologies such as, ‘cookies,’ ‘web beacons/web bugs,’ ‘action tags,’ ‘.gif tags,’ and ‘JavaScript’ (together, “Tracking Tools”). Tracking Tools are files or tools that are placed on your computer in order to identify your Web browser and the activities of your computer on the Newsmax Offerings. Newsmax uses these technologies to customize and enhance the Internet experience of individual users. When you revisit the Newsmax Offerings, Newsmax may recognize you by a Tracking Tool and customize your experience accordingly. For example, once you have completed the registration process, a cookie will be used to remember your registration preferences. See the Digital Advertising & Analytics section [insert link to this section] of this Privacy Policy to learn more about the use of this information and the choices available to you. You may decline Internet cookies by using the appropriate feature of your Web browser software, if available. If cookies are disabled, however, all features of the Newsmax Offerings may not operate as intended. Information about the procedure you are required to follow in order to disable cookies can be found on your Internet browser provider’s website.

We believe Tracking Tool technologies add value to the user experience, and the information obtained through these technologies is not sold or otherwise made available to third parties by Newsmax, other than as may from time to time be specified in this Privacy Policy.

For more information on our Tracking Tool technologies, see our [Cookie & Similar Technologies Policy](https://www.newsmax.com/cookiepolicy/).

**Use and Sharing of Personal Data**

Newsmax uses Personal Data and Monitoring Data it collects for editorial and feedback purposes, and to deliver relevant advertising, statistical analysis of users’ behavior, product development, delivering products and services, providing customer support, customizing and improving the content and layout of the Newsmax Offerings, completing business transactions, administering orders for goods through our website store(s), administering individual accounts, processing applications for employment, meeting government regulatory requirements such as sales tax collection, for marketing purposes, to maintain the security of our Sites, and as otherwise disclosed at the time of collection or use. Monitoring Data may be used for internal or external purposes such as researching and identifying market segments and needs, and marketing and promotion.

Newsmax may share data with service providers, affiliates, and subsidiaries in connection with the services we provide, including with these other businesses within our corporate family: Humanix Books, Newsmax Broadcasting, Medix Select, and Crown Atlantic. Newsmax uses service providers to provide email and direct mail services to Newsmax.

Newsmax may share the information to unaffiliated third parties if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary (a) to comply with applicable laws, rules, or regulations, or to preserve Newsmax’s legal rights in the Newsmax Offerings’ content, whether the same arises from contract or through force of law; (b) to provide you with any services, information, special offers, promotions or products you requested or consented to and to allow us to perform other activities related to such services and products; or (c) to operate these Newsmax Offerings and other of Newsmax’s systems .

Newsmax may share information with a sponsor or other third party that is interested in providing you with products and services (“Third-Party Providers”). You may instruct us at any time not to share your Personal Data with such Third-Party Providers by contacting us in the manner provided under “Your Choices Regarding Personal Data Collection and Use.”

We may share information that has been de-identified or aggregated without restriction.

Newsmax is not responsible for any further use or disclosure of your Personal Data by Third-Party Providers; such use or disclosure is governed by the Third-Party Providers’ privacy policies.

Newsmax reserves the right to transfer the information it collects to successors to the relevant portion of any of Newsmax’s businesses or to independent contractors it engages to assist with or perform on Newsmax’s behalf any of the foregoing activities. Also, if Newsmax’s assets are subject to a claim in bankruptcy, Personal Data and Monitoring Data may be an asset subject to the claims of a trustee in bankruptcy and may be available to Newsmax’s creditors. In addition, Newsmax reserves the right to use Personal Data to contact you regarding your account status and changes to this Privacy Policy or any other policies, agreements or transactions relevant to your use of the Newsmax Offerings. Newsmax will take reasonable steps to maintain the integrity of the collected data so that it is reliable and appropriate for the foregoing uses.

**Activity of Our Business**

Newsmax may use the Personal Data you share with us to provide you with the information or product(s) you signed up for or purchased. No Personal Data will be given to any third-party platform for advertising or marketing purposes. Contact information for texting groups will not be shared to third parties.

We may use third-party service providers, such as ad networks, to perform certain advertising activities on our behalf, such as retargeting, but we will not provide them with your Personal Data. Newsmax advertising does not use segments designed to target children under sixteen (16) years of age to serve or optimize advertisements. Newsmax does not use automatic decision-making. We may engage in profiling for targeted marketing purposes.

**Digital Advertising and Analytics**

We may partner with ad networks and other ad serving providers (“Advertising Providers”) who serve ads on behalf of us and others on non-affiliated sites and mobile apps. Some of those ads may be personalized, meaning that they are intended to be relevant to you based on information Advertising Providers collect about your visits to the Site, other sites or apps, and elsewhere over time, including that data across associated devices. This type of advertising is known as interest-based advertising.

Newsmax adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) Self-Regulatory Principles and to the European Digital Advertising Alliance (“EDAA”) Principles in the European Union (“EU”) in connection with this interest-based advertising activity. U.S. individuals may visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices> while EU individuals can visit [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) to learn more about this type of advertising and how to opt out of this advertising by companies participating in these consumer choice tools. You may also use tools provided by mobile operating system providers, such as limit ad tracking, to opt-out of interest-based advertising on your mobile device to opt-out of interest-based advertising on your mobile device. Your choices will apply to this browser or mobile device. If you delete your cookies or use a different browser or mobile device, you may need to renew your opt-out choice. Note that electing to opt out will not stop advertising from appearing in your browser or applications. It may make the ads you see less relevant to your interests.

We may also work with third parties that collect data about your use of the Sites and other sites or apps over time for non-advertising purposes. Newsmax uses Google Analytics and other third-party services to improve the performance of the Site and for analytics and marketing purposes. For more information about how Google Analytics collects and uses data when you use our Site, visit <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>, and to opt out of Google Analytics, visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

**International Visitors**

This section applies to those that visit our website from the European Economic Area, United Kingdom, and Switzerland.

Newsmax processes Personal Data with your consent (e.g., when Newsmax processes Personal Data to provide goods and services you request, such as to provide Personal Data to third parties at your direction).

On other occasions, Newsmax may process Personal Data when it needs to do this to fulfill a contract or where required to do this by law. This includes processing your Personal Data when you subscribe to publications or purchase products.

If necessary, Newsmax may also process Personal Data when it is in Newsmax’s legitimate interests to do this (e.g., for customer service or to respond to your requests for information) and when these interests are not overridden by your data protection rights.

Please be aware that the Personal Data we collect may be transferred to and maintained on servers or databases located outside your state, province, country, or other jurisdiction, where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your location. If you are located outside of the United States, please be advised that we process and store Personal Data in the United States.

You have a right to the following:

  * •          To request access to the Personal Data we hold about you;
  * •          To request that we rectify or erase your Personal Data;
  * •          To request that we restrict or block the processing of your Personal Data;
  * •          Under certain circumstances, to receive Personal Data about you that we store and transmit to another without hindrance from us, including requesting that we provide your Personal Data directly to another, i.e., a right to data portability; and
  * •          Where we previously obtained your consent, to withdraw consent to processing your Personal Data.

To exercise these rights, contact our Data Protection Officer using the “Contact Us” section below. Please be aware that Newsmax may be unable to afford these rights to you under certain circumstances, such as if we are legally prevented from doing so.

Additionally, you have the right to lodge a complaint against us. To do so, contact the supervisory authority in your country of residence.

**Retention**

We will process and store your information only for the period necessary to achieve the purpose of the storage, or as permitted by law. The criteria used to determine the period of storage of information is the respective statutory retention period or Newsmax internal data retention policies. After expiration of that period, the corresponding information is routinely deleted, as long as it is no longer necessary for the fulfillment of a contract or the initiation of a contract.

**Your Choices Regarding Personal Data Collection and Use**

You may choose to receive promotional correspondence from Newsmax and its marketing partners by checking the appropriate box when you register or by contacting Newsmax at [customerservice@newsmax.com](mailto:customerservice@newsmax.com) or 800-485-4350. You may modify, correct, change, delete, or update Personal Data that Newsmax has collected via the Newsmax Offerings or request that your Personal Data be removed from Newsmax’s database. In any instance, our removal of such information may require you to register again with Newsmax in the event you later wish full access to the Newsmax Offerings.

**Links**

The Newsmax Offerings may contain links to other websites maintained by third parties (“Other Sites”), including social media pages, either as a hyperlink or through a direct data feed accessed by you. Newsmax does not control, endorse, and is not responsible for, the privacy practices or the content of these websites. You should review the applicable privacy policies in connection with your use of such third party websites.

The Newsmax Offerings may also include integrated social media tools or “plug-ins,” such as social networking tools offered by third parties. If you use these tools to share Personal Data or you otherwise interact with these features on the Sites, those companies may collect information about you and may use and share such information in accordance with your account settings, including by sharing such information with the general public. Your interactions with these third parties are governed by their privacy notices. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy notices of any accounts you create and use.

**Security Measures**

Newsmax has established reasonable precautions to protect collected Personal Data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction, which include contractual, administrative, physical, and technical steps. Technical measures include use of firewall protection and encryption technology where appropriate. Please note that while Newsmax has endeavored to create secure and reliable sites and mobile application(s) for users, the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to/from Newsmax or the Newsmax Offerings or via email cannot be guaranteed.

**Changes to Our Privacy Notice**

Newsmax will from time to time review and revise these practices. We will post any changes to this Privacy Policy here. Please refer back to this Privacy Policy on a regular basis.

**Contact Information for Newsmax**

To contact Newsmax in its role as a data controller, please contact us in the following ways:

If you choose to contact Newsmax via e-mail regarding this Privacy Policy, or Other Agreements, please email [terms@newsmax.com](mailto:terms@newsmax.com) and mark the subject heading of your e-mail “Privacy Inquiry” or “Purchaser/Subscriber Inquiry,” respectively;

If you would like to contact a Newsmax’s customer service agent, and for questions or concerns regarding Newsmax’s data protection practices, email [customerservice@newsmax.com](mailto:customerservice@newsmax.com);

If you would like to contact Newsmax’s copyright agent, email [copyright@newsmax.com](mailto:copyright@newsmax.com); or

To contact us via postal mail: Newsmax Media, P.O. Box 20989, West Palm Beach, FL 33416.
